# **Aaron Niskin**

3415 Chase Ave — Miami Beach, FL 33140 **☎** (305) 894-6475 • ☑ aaron@niskin.org • ☑ aaron.niskin.org

HR Department October 3, 2016

Blackrock 40 East 52nd Street 10022 New York, NY

Dear Sir or Madam,

I am a first year graduate student in the Data Science program at the New College of Florida. I would like to spend my 2017 summer learning and Internship with the Analyst Program at BlackRock. As a Mathematician entering the field of statistical computing and Machine Learning, there is no better place to be than Blackrock I believe I have the educational background, academic achievement, and passion to be an outstanding member of your team.

I have previously worked full time as a content developer at XYZ. I was in the Quant team at XYZ where I got to hone my quantitative and analytical skills. As a part of my job I had to constantly communicate with the publishing and marketing team of the company which improved my communication and team leadership skills. In addition, at the University XYZ, I currently taking various courses in Fixed Income, Statistical Modelling, and Portfolio Management where I am learning various financial models and quantitative methods used in the finance industry. I believe that the theoretical and practical knowledge I gained from my graduate program along with my passion to learn new things, will enable me to significantly contribute to your company.

I hope that you will find me well qualified for the Summer Intern Position and I would like to reiterate my strong interest to discuss this opportunity and my qualifications with you further.

Thank you very much for your time and consideration.

Sincerely yours,

#### Aaron Niskin

Attached: curriculum vitæ

# **Aaron Niskin**

3415 Chase Ave - Miami Beach, FL 33140

☎ (305) 894-6475 • ⊠ aaron@niskin.org • ७ aaron.niskin.org

## **Skills and Languages**

Advanced: JAVASCRIPT, HTML, PYTHON\*, R\* | Spanish

Intermediate: Clojure, Scheme, Hoplon, CSS, MySQL, PostgreSQL, NodeJS | Hebrew

Basic: JAVA, HASKELL, MONGODB, LATEX, MATLAB, OCTAVE | German

\*Projected - based on current workload

### **Education**

New College of Florida Sarasota Master's In Data Science 2016-(2018)

#### Florida International University

Miami

Bachelor of Science | Mathematics Minors | Physics and English 2012-2015

- Graduated Cum Laude GPA 3.64 (3.79 in major)
- Dean's List (6 times)

Miami Dade College Miami Associate of Arts 2010-2011

- Graduated with Honors GPA 3.74 out of 4.00
- Dean's List (5 times)
- Physics Award

# **Experience**

Florida Vocation Institute

Miami

Computer Science Instructor

2015-2016

- Taught and created syllabi for courses in HTML, CSS, CSS-Frameworks, JavaScript, SQL, MongoDB, NodeJS, Functional-Programming, and Basic-Logic
- Created a free online course intended to teach aspiring students about the above subjects through interesting projects (currently live at www.fvi-grad.com)

#### Math-Busters (www.Math-Busters.com)

Miami

Co-founder and Math/Science/Computing Tutor

2010-2015

- Co-founded a successful income generating tutoring company (www.Math-Busters.com)
- Tutored all levels of students from Elementary School to upper-level University students

Infantryman

# 1-38 Infantry Regiment, 4/2 ID, US Army

Fort Lewis. WA

2006-2009

- Deployed to Iraq for OIF V from 2007-2008
- Held Team Leader, Rifleman, M-240B Machine Gunner, M-249 SAW gunner, RTO, Grenadier, and Marksman positions
- Combat Lifesaver certification
- Fought forest fires in Winthrop, Washington.

## 478th Civilian Affairs Battalion, US Army

Perrine, FL

Civil Affairs Specialist

2004-2006

- Trained at the John F. Kennedy Special Warfare Center and School in Fort Bragg, NC for 6 months.
- Obtained Secret Clearance